<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>joe di castro</title><link>http://joedicastro.com</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://joedicastro.com/feeds/tags/vim.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 16:53:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vim as Python code editor</title><link>http://joedicastro.com/vim-as-python-code-editor.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is a translation from the original one in Spanish, &lt;a href="http://joedicastro.com/vim-como-editor-de-codigo-python.html"&gt;Vim como
editor de codigo Python&lt;/a&gt;, published in April 2013.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an article that I've always wanted to write: "Vim as Python IDE". Two
years ago I had a Vim configuration that I thought that was just right for this,
even a half-written article. But while I was polishing the config and finishing
the article, a bunch of similar articles appeared in the internet and after
reading them I realized something: many of them were already obsolete at the
time they were published. And I say this because many of them employed plugins
that were outdated by the emerge of other fresh and more powerful. In fact in
the last two years, the Vim environment has evolved too much that from all the
plugins that I used in those days (and the ones pending to test), currently I'm
using only 10% of them, the rest are new ones. And this "race" to provide new
and more powerful features for Vim continues nowadays, with some great tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, as one is adding plugins and "tuning" his config, there comes
a time when you don't know where and what is already mapped, even no
remember at all the plugins at features available for you, and which you
implemented with so much effort and time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="my_configuration"&gt;My configuration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given these two premises I had the idea of kill two birds with one stone:
&lt;strong&gt;Document my Vim setup&lt;/strong&gt;. What I'm trying with this is that should work for me
as sort of cheat-sheet to remember all that I had available in my config, and at
the same time to have a coherent mapping and avoid duplicates (at least is the
idea). By the other hand, it works also to demonstrate all the Vim's potential
to edit Python code and compete with almost any IDE, but with all the advantages
of the unique Vim's way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to have a continuously updated document with respect to my current
setup, What better article than this, an always updated one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the link to this doc, &lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt;, included in my dotfiles
repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/joedicastro/dotfiles/tree/master/vim"&gt;Doc at GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;English is not my mother tongue, so maybe the article (and the doc) can be full
of grammatical mistakes due to my poor English. Sorry for that, I did my best.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">joe di castro</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 16:53:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://joedicastro.com/vim-as-python-code-editor.html</guid><category>vim</category><category>python</category><category>editores</category><category>linux</category></item><item><title>Vim como editor de codigo Python</title><link>http://joedicastro.com/vim-como-editor-de-codigo-python.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Este es un articulo que siempre he deseado escribir: &lt;em&gt;Vim como IDE para Python&lt;/em&gt;.
Hace dos años tenia una configuración de Vim que creía ideal para esto e incluso
el articulo a medio escribir. Pero a medida que iba puliendo la configuración y
completando el articulo, empezaron a surgir varios similares en la red (sobre
todo en inglés) y caí en la cuenta de algo: muchos ya estaban obsoletos al
publicarse. Y cuando digo esto lo digo porque muchos de estos artículos
empleaban plugins que se habían quedado desfasados por la aparición de otros mas
recientes y potentes. De hecho en los dos últimos años ha cambiado tanto el
panorama en el ecosistema en torno a Vim, que de la lista de plugins que
empleaba por aquel entonces (y los que tenía pendientes de probar) solo empleo
actualmente el 10%, el resto son nuevos. Y esta "carrera" por nutrir a Vim de
características nuevas y cada vez más potentes continua hoy en día, con algunas
herramientas excelentes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Por otro lado, a medida que uno va añadiendo plugins y "tuneando" su
configuración llega un momento que ya no sabes ni donde tienes "mapeados" los
atajos, ni recuerdas todas las características que tienes a tu disposición y
tanto tiempo empleaste en implantar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="mi_configuraci+n"&gt;Mi configuración&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partiendo de estas dos premisas se me ocurrió una idea de atajar los dos
problemas de un golpe: &lt;strong&gt;Documentar mi configuración&lt;/strong&gt;. Lo que trato por un lado
es que me sirva personalmente tanto para recordar todo lo que tengo disponible
en el editor, como para poder organizar coherentemente todos los atajos y evitar
duplicados. Por el otro lado, también me sirve para la idea de demostrar el
potencial que tiene Vim a la hora de ser un editor de código que puede estar a
la altura de cualquier IDE, pero con todas las ventajas inherentes a la
filosofía única de Vim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La idea es que el documento esté permanentemente actualizado a la par que mi
configuración real, ¿que mejor articulo que este, que siempre estará
actualizado?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La configuración está documentada en un &lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt; dentro de la carpeta de Vim
del repositorio de mis dotfiles. Aquí se puede acceder directamente a mi
configuración y ver el documento. Actualmente el articulo está en Inglés, aquí
se pude acceder a la última revisión en español.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/joedicastro/dotfiles/blob/a87b42deb9c1132c8f801bb91d119f0b26d21d68/vim/README.md"&gt;Documento en GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">joe di castro</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 10:29:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://joedicastro.com/vim-como-editor-de-codigo-python.html</guid><category>vim</category><category>python</category><category>editores</category><category>linux</category></item></channel></rss>